merchbar.com 2016-04-01

# Privacy Policy

PRIVACY POLICY 

Last updated on June 24, 2015 

Our Privacy Policy is designed to provide clarity about the information we collect and how we use it to provide a better user experience. By accepting our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service in registration, you consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us as described in Section 12 (“Contact Us”). 

1\. INTRODUCTION 

Merchbar operates applications for mobile devices and Merchbar branded websites (the “Service”). In this policy, “Merchbar” refers to Merchbar, Inc. and its Affiliates, which means subsidiaries, parent companies, joint ventures and other corporate entities under common ownership. We may also refer to Merchbar as “we” or “us”.   
This Privacy Policy describes: the information we collect, how we do so and the purposes of our collection how we use and with whom we share such information how you can access and update such information the choices you can make about how we collect, use and share your information how we protect the information we store about you 

2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

When you interact with the Service, via any Merchbar mobile application, at www.merchbar.com, or any Merchbar-owned or Affiliate-owned website, we may collect and store information from you directly as described below: 

2.1 Registration Information 

We may allow you to “register” with us to create an account or profile within the Service. In the registration process you may be required to provide the following information: your age or birthday (for age screening and/or to better understand who our users are); your first and last names; your e-mail address; a password and other information that helps us confirm that it is you accessing your account.   
We may also offer you the option to complete a user profile that is visible to other Merchbar users. Your user profile may include: a profile photo; one or more usernames; your gender; biographic details that you provide; links to your profiles on various social networking sites; and a Merchbar user ID number that is created by Merchbar and used to identify your profile.   
The Merchbar user ID number used to identify your account and profile will be public and will appear in the URL of your profile page, but will only permit access to information that is considered public or that you have designated as public in your settings.   
Your first and last names and profile picture are considered “public” on Merchbar websites and search engines may index this publicly available information. When we offer profiles, we may also offer functionality that allows you to opt-out of public indexing of your public profile information.   
2.2 Information We Receive or Collect When You Use the Service on a Mobile Device   
If you access the Service from your mobile telephone or other mobile device, including iPads and tablets, we collect mobile device identifiers, including MAC Address, and IP Address. We may create and assign to your device an identifier that is similar to an account number. We may collect the name you have associated with your device, device type, telephone number, country, and any other information you choose to provide, such as user name or e-mail address. We may also collect geo-location information each time you access the Service from a mobile device unless you have disabled the geo-location feature in the device settings. 

2.3 Payment Information 

If you make a purchase in connection with the Service, we will collect the billing and financial information necessary to process your charges, which may include your postal and e-mail addresses. Merchbar may also receive the billing and payment information that you provide when your purchase is processed by another party. 

2.4 Customer Support Correspondence When you ask for assistance from our Customer Support team, we will collect and store the contact information you provide (generally your name and e-mail address), information about your activity on the Service, and your user ID number. We will also store the correspondence and any information contained within. 

2.5 SMS Notifications, Push Notifications & Local Notifications We receive and store the information you provide, including your telephone number, when you sign up to have SMS notifications sent directly to your mobile phone. You can adjust the types of notifications you receive and when you receive them by editing your SMS notification settings.   
With your consent we may send push notifications to your mobile device to provide updates and other relevant messages. You can manage push notifications from the “options” or “settings” page. You may also be able to manage them from your device’s settings page for the Service. 2.6 Technical and Usage Information 

When you access our websites or the Service, we collect (i) certain technical information about your mobile device or computer system, including MAC Address, IP Address and mobile device ID; and (ii) usage statistics about your interactions with the Service. This information is typically collected through the use of server log files or web log files (“Log Files”), mobile device software development kits and tracking technologies like browser cookies to collect and analyze certain types of technical information. Some of the cookies the Service places on your computer are linked to your user ID number(s). For more information on how we utilize cookies and other tracking technologies please review the “Cookies and Automated Information Collection” portion of Section 3 (“How we Collect Information about You”). 

3\. HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU 

We may collect information about you in any one or more of the following ways: 

3.1 Information about Users 

When you use the Service, Merchbar collects and stores certain information that you provide directly or through a third party website. We may also collect information about your interaction with other users of the Service. The bulk of this information is collected and stored through the use of Log Files, which are files on our web servers that record actions taken on our websites. 

3.2 Communications Features 

You may be able to take part in certain activities on our websites or by using the Service that give you the opportunity to communicate or share information not just with Merchbar, but also with other users of our Service. We may record and store archives of these communications on our servers to protect the safety and well being of our users and our rights and property in connection with the service. You acknowledge and consent to the recording and storage of such communications for these purposes. 

3.3 Cookies and Automated Information Collection 

When you access the Service, we collect certain technical information in order to (i) analyze the usage of our sites and services; (ii) provide a more personalized experience; and (iii) manage advertising. We and service providers acting on our behalf, such as Google Analytics, use Log Files and tracking technologies to collect and analyze certain types of technical information, including cookies, IP addresses, device type, device identifiers, browser types, browser language, referring and exit pages, and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of activity on our websites, and other similar information. In some cases, we will associate this information with your user ID number for our internal use.   
We may also employ other technologies including (i) web beacons, which allow us to know if a certain page was visited or whether an e-mail was opened; (ii) tracking pixels, which allow us to advertise more efficiently by excluding our current users from certain promotional messages, identifying the source of a new installation or delivering ads to you on other websites; and (iii) local shared objects also known as flash cookies, which help us to prevent fraud, remember your in-Service preferences and speed up load times.   
You can set your web browser to warn you about attempts to place cookies on your computer or limit the type of cookies you allow. Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies and cookie management tools available in a web browser may not remove flash cookies. If you disable cookies, you may lose some of the features and functionality of the Service, as cookies are necessary to track and enhance your activities within the Service. 

4\. HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

In general, we collect, store and use your information to provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience. For example, we may use information collected from you in any one or more of the following ways:   
to create your user accounts   
to identify and suggest connections with other users   
to enable user-to-user communications   
to provide technical support and respond to user inquiries   
to prevent fraud or potentially illegal activities, and enforce our Terms of Service   
to deliver and target advertising   
to notify users of updates   
to solicit feedback to improve Merchbar products and services and customize your user experience   
to inform users about new products or promotional offers   
One important use of your information is communication. If you have provided your e-mail address to Merchbar, we’ll use it to respond to (i) customer support inquiries, and (ii) keep you informed of your activity within the Service. We may also send promotional e-mail messages and promotional SMS messages (“Promotional Communications”) directly or in partnership with parties other than Merchbar. Each Promotional Communication will generally offer recipients choices about receiving additional messages. 

5\. SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION 

We will share your information (in some cases personal information) with third parties, that is parties other than Merchbar, in the following circumstances: 

5.1 Third-Party Service Providers 

We will provide your information to third-party companies to perform services on our behalf, including payment processing, product delivery, data analysis, e-mail delivery, hosting services, customer service and to assist us in our marketing efforts. 

5.2 Business Partners 

We may share your information with third parties in order to further the business of Merchbar, which determination shall be made on a case-by-case basis and in our sole discretion. 

5.3 Other Users 

The Service supports and may encourage interaction among users. Other users may see your name, profile and descriptions of your activity. 

5.4 Advertising of Third-Party Products and Services We may share personal information, including your email address, with third-party advertisers for their direct marketing purposes.   
We may also share (i) aggregated information (information about you and other users collectively, but not specifically identifiable to you); (ii) anonymous information; and (iii) certain technical information (including IP Addresses, MAC Addresses for mobile devices and mobile device IDs) to develop and deliver targeted advertising in the Service and on the websites of third parties. We may also allow advertisers to collect these types of information within the Service and they may share it with us. Advertisers may collect this information through the use of tracking technologies like browser cookies and web beacons. The information collected may be used to offer you targeted ad-selection and delivery in order to personalize your user experience by ensuring that advertisements for products and services you see will appeal to you, a practice known as behavioral advertising, and to undertake web analytics (i.e. to analyze traffic and other end user activity to improve your experience). Our collection, use, and disclosure of anonymous or aggregated information are not subject to any of the restrictions in this Privacy Policy. 

5.5 Safety, Security and Compliance with Law 

Your information, and the contents of all of your online communications (including without limitation chat text, voice communications, IP addresses and your personal information) may be accessed and monitored as necessary to provide the Service and may be disclosed: (i) when we have a good faith belief that we are required to disclose the information in response to legal process (for example, a court order, search warrant or subpoena); (ii) to satisfy any applicable laws or regulations (iii) where we believe that the Service is being used in the commission of a crime, including to report such criminal activity or to exchange information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; (iv) when we have a good faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the health and/or safety of you, another person or the public generally; and (v) in order to protect the rights or property of Merchbar, including to enforce our Terms of Service. 

5.6 Sale or Merger 

In the event that Merchbar undergoes a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, we may transfer all of your information, including personal information, to the successor organization in such transition. If material changes to our privacy practices will occur as a result of the business transition, we will notify you and other users of the business transition prior to transferring your personal information. 

6\. OUR POLICIES CONCERNING CHILDREN 

Our Service is not intended for children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from such children. Children under the age of 13 should not use our websites or the Service at any time. In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently gathered personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take reasonable measures to promptly erase such information from our records. 

7\. HOW TO ACCESS AND UPDATE YOUR INFORMATION 

If you no longer want Merchbar to make active use of your information, you may send an e-mail to support@merchbar.com. Place “Delete My Account” in the subject line and include your first name, last name, e-mail address and user ID number. We will respond to your request within 30 days. Please note that certain records, for example those pertaining to payments or customer service matters, will be retained for legal and accounting purposes. If you have sent or posted content on the Service, we may not be able to delete it. If you wish to review or change the information Merchbar has about you, e-mail us at the address provided herein. You may change your e-mail preferences at any time, by visiting your e-mail preference page. You can turn off push notifications by visiting the “options” or “settings” page. You can stop further use of your geo-location by visiting your device’s settings for the relevant application or the “settings” page for the relevant application. If you have additional questions about this Privacy Policy, contact us at support@merchbar.com. 

8\. YOUR SHARING AND MESSAGING OPTIONS 

8.1 Opting out of Promotional Communications 

You can choose to opt out of receiving additional promotional e-mails from Merchbar by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in any such e-mail, or visiting the e-mail preference page. Please note that once we receive your request, it may take an additional period of time for your opt-out to become effective. 

8.2 Opting Out of Other Communications 

You can opt out of receiving SMS messages by texting STOP to the number we send from for that particular SMS program. When we receive an opt-out message from you for SMS messages, we may send a message confirming our receipt of your opt-out. When you install our apps on your mobile device you can choose to receive push notifications. You can turn off push notifications by visiting the “options” or “settings” page within the relevant app. Note that if you opt-out of our Promotional Communications or other forms of communication, we may still e-mail or communicate with you from time to time if we need to provide you with information or if we need to request information from you with respect to a transaction initiated by you or for other legitimate non-marketing reasons. 

9\. PRIVACY POLICIES OF LINKED SITES AND ADVERTISERS Our websites may contain advertisements from companies other than Merchbar that may link to their own websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. If you have any questions about how these other websites use your information, you should review their policies and contact them directly. 

10\. SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION Merchbar implements reasonable security measures to protect the security of your information both online and offline, and we are committed to the protection of customer information. For user accounts registered with Merchbar, profile information is protected by the password each member uses to access their online account. It is important that you protect and maintain the security of your account and that you immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your account. If you forget the password to your Merchbar account, the website allows you to request that instructions be sent to you that explain how to reset your password. When you sign into your account or enter payment information (such as a credit card number when purchasing virtual currency), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (“SSL”). While we take reasonable precautions against possible security breaches of our websites and our customer databases and records, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe (including your account password), and to log out of your account after use. Unfortunately, the transmission of information over the Internet is not completely secure. Although we strive to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data while it is being transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we have procedures and security features in place to try to prevent unauthorized access. 

11\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY 

We may make P3P – compact machine-readable – policies and headers available. If we do so, we will try to ensure that they are consistent with this human readable policy. However, in the event of a conflict between a machine-readable policy and this policy, this (human readable) policy will control. If we decide to make material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you and other users by placing a notice on our website or by sending you a notice to the e-mail address we have on file for you. You should periodically check www.merchbar.com and this privacy page for updates. 

12\. CONTACT US 

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy and/or practices, please send an e-mail to support@merchbar.com. All other inquiries should be directed to Our Support Page.   
Contact:   
Merchbar   
182 Howard Street   
Suite 212   
San Francisco   
California   
94105-1611
